<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Serious advice, presented to the common council of the city of London</title>
            <author>Whiston, James, 1637?-1707.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A65665</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12338909</idno>
  <idno type="VID">59837</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240973880</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing W1687</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224591</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12338909</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A65665)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 59837)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 929:31)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Serious advice, presented to the common council of the city of London</title>
                  <author>Whiston, James, 1637?-1707.</author>
                  <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8, [1], 6-7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1681?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Attributed to James Whiston. cf. NUC pre-1956.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">London (England) --  Politics and government.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:59837:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Serious Advice,</hi> PRESENTED TO THE Common Council OF THE CITY OF LONDON.</head>
            <p>THAT State or City which would keep it's self in good Order and free from Ruine, must cherish the just Impeachments, and Accusations of the People, against those who contrary to Law through Ambition, Avarice, Pride, Cruelty, Oppression, Violation, Extortion or Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> seeks to destroy their Liberties Properties and Right; and though after an unwelcome and unexpected Desolution of our Wise State Physitions; yet, by God's Mercy, goodness of our King, and Prudence of a Parliament to as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>semble at <hi>Oxford;</hi> we hope to see an unseperable Union betwixt his Majesty and his People, and the many grievances (which this Land Mourns under) redressed; illegal proceedings punisht; and Oppression so discountenanced that succeeding Times shall not dare to Barter Justice for Gold, nor Sacrifice our Priviledges to Riot, not truck away the Liberty of their Country for a little Court Holy Water.</p>
            <p>The Nation being redress't and secured against Tyranny and Oppression, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> will never seek after other Liberty, but rejoyce under his most Sacred Majesty, and Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Parliament. It cannot sure be censured as unseasonable (because always just and necessary) to remind (for I presume not to instruct) those in whose power the remedy lies, of an eminent inconvenience to the Publick, which is the Sale of Offices; concerning which, I shall chiefly refer my discourse at present to the Honourable City of <hi>London,</hi> the Envy of <hi>Europe, Rome</hi>'s Terrour, <hi>England</hi>'s Heart, where the Vital Spirits circulate, and the grand Pattern by whose Measures sinaller Corporations are apt to make their Presidents.</p>
            <p>That which I offer to consideration is, That 'tis dishonourable and of very ill consequence to expose Publick Offices and Places to Sale. For it deflow'rs the Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin purity of Justice by stoping the Avenues that lead to her Pallace, with Merce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:59837:2"/>encumbrances, exposes the Purchasers to almost inevitable Temptations, and gives an inlet and plausible Colour for defending Injustice, Bribary, Extortion and Oppression. But to double and treble the value, to manage them for the best advantage of the Seller, and to put him upon the Rack of improvement too; what is it but to bespeak the unfittest Men, the greatest Knaves or Fools, that we can meet with, to manage these Affairs and Places in which Justice, Reason and Prudence, require the Honestest and most upright Persons that can be procured.</p>
            <p>Because the Fees of the Atturnies Clarks, Sarjeants, Goalers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the Courts of <hi>London</hi> have increas'd, through the increase of Injustice by reason of the too fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent Malicious and Impertinent actions, and general corruption among them: Yet no Magistrate ought from thence to raise the value of an unlawful Sale, because he finds a sort of People <hi>thriving and doing well,</hi> by living and doing <hi>ill.</hi> And the same reason holds against the Keepers of Prisoners, who would never give such ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessive Rates for their Places; were they not wicked grinders of the Poor: Men that lay the whole design of their advantage upon the Calamities of the Miserable; at which the Magistrates are supposed too too much to connive, who suffer their Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fers to be fill'd with these Golden temptations, because he sees them cloathed so Rich, and and grow so sat upon the Ruines of the Unfortunate; which is quite con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the Office of the true Magistrate, who ought to have a careful Eye upon the growth of <hi>Oppression,</hi> to curb and remove the Exorbitancies of Injustice, and to <hi>seare</hi> away the <hi>proud Flesh</hi> of Avarice and Rapine, and not to Sell Impunity to the Evil doer. Therefore it is not to be question'd, but infallibly asserted, That whoever receives Money for any Place, whereof the Sale is not to be warrented, does but re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive a <hi>Publick Bribe,</hi> which only custome, and perhaps too common connivance justifies. For <hi>never any Man,</hi> saith <hi>Tacitus, ever came to any Office by Money, but he was forced to exercise his Authority wickedly and unjustly.</hi> He that buys must sell, or he looses by the Bargain. Which makes the Pubilck Offices of <hi>London,</hi> like Bry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers to which Sheep repair for shelter, loose a Lock.</p>
            <p>If an appeal be made to Holy Scripture, there is most certainly no Learning un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Sun so Chymical, that can extract the least drop of Authority from thence, for the Sale of Publick justice or it's Dependancies; but excessive Penalties it may find enough upon all manner of Extortion and upon all those that connive at, &amp; suffer It; so severely menaced, and so truly threatned by him, that never sails to perform, that nothing but a fatal <hi>Irony</hi> can excuse the contempt and neglect thereof, as if the <hi>Ears</hi> of the profit could not <hi>hear</hi> the <hi>cries</hi> of the Poor for the <hi>thundring noise</hi> of God's judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; to severely denounc'd on their behalf. However they who require more particular satifaction, may read that excellent Oration of the Prophet <hi>Samuel,</hi> which he made upon the resignation of his Government.</p>
            <p>Being thus banished from the Common-wealth of <hi>Israel,</hi> this Tenent finds no better entertainment among the <hi>Heathen,</hi> with whom we find these two Maxims, like two Golden Pillars supporting the most flourishing and most Victorious Cities in the World, which <hi>Aristotle</hi> hath not been a little industri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous to maintain; First, <hi>That the Sale of Offices is the greatest wrong that can be offer'd to a Commonwealth.</hi> Secondly, <hi>That mony ought not to buy those Places, which may, nay ought to be the reward of Virtue, and are the sittest means to supply the necessities of good Men.</hi> The Sale of Offices in the flourishing Times of the <hi>Athenians</hi> was abomina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, and by the <hi>Lacedemonians</hi> expleded as a Crime: And the <hi>Roman</hi> Empire in its increase and flourishing condition, Fined and Punish'd those that sought Offices In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>justly; and they then first bred dissention among themselves, and their own destru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction when they brook'd so patiently the <hi>Sardoni</hi> scoff bf <hi>Jugurth, All things at</hi> Rome, <hi>are to be had for Money.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Certainly, the <hi>Persian Cambyses</hi> had been too severe, when he Flea'd one of his Judges for Extortion, had he sold him his Place, much more had he Farm'd it to him, at a rack Rent: Nor can we believe the same Judges Son would have given an exacted Sum to sit upon his Father's Skin, which he was forc'd to receive for his Cushin being placed in his Father's room, to terrifie him from the same Offence, which the King then told him would deserve the same punishment.</p>
            <p>I might here repeat more of <hi>History,</hi> but my design is not Prolixity; unless any one should be so <hi>Hardy</hi> as to deny the Truth of what is here set down, or otherwise at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt to shadow and be smear this Truth with Varnish of self-designing Rhetorick,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:59837:2"/>or Logical distinctions. Nor can he be other than some contentious or interested Person, who will oppose the experienc'd Precedents of so many Wise, Illustrious, and Potent Law-givers.</p>
            <p>To rise then from History to <hi>Reason,</hi> we meet with a <hi>Thesis,</hi> fairly bordering upon the Law of Nature, as undeniable as Truth it self; That there is nothing Arms a <hi>Purchaser</hi> with a more <hi>confident defence</hi> of his unjust dealings, than <hi>Money</hi> given for an Imployment. It makes him that he <hi>blushes</hi> not to be accused of Rigour and <hi>Extortion,</hi> to be Arraigned for <hi>Violence,</hi> nor values he the frowns of Magistracy, while with a daring Forehead he is able to upbraid his Superiour, telling him, he had not his place for <hi>nothing,</hi> but <hi>paid</hi> soundly for it, and therefore hopes he shall not be debar'd from making the <hi>best advantage</hi> of what he has purchas'd at so dear a rate. A thing so obvious, that reprove him never so sharply, never so severely, it seems <hi>Collusive</hi> and meerly Commination, so little does it signifie. For turn him out of Possession, and the succeeding Chapman is discouraged. Nor does the Judg himself scape the sinutty censure of Self-interest and Partiality, that he only removes the Old one in hopes of a better Bargain from a Successor, that must be worse be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cause he gives more for it. Here Justice may be said to be throughly <hi>Blind,</hi> while the Seller and Abbetter throw away the vail of Impartiality, and press down their <hi>Eyelids</hi> with their own Fingers. Thus, first Rate Offences, Misdemeanours of the upper Form must be conniv'd at and palliated, for fear of <hi>spoiling the Market.</hi> As for <hi>Peccadillo</hi>'s, and petty Oppressions, they are little or not at all regarded: Yet these are the <hi>little Vermin</hi> that insensibly devour the poor and needy, that have most need of succour, What is the difference between the Canker that <hi>undiscernibly</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sumes, and the destructive speed of <hi>Aqua fortis?</hi> They both destroy: But the Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker <hi>far more</hi> as being less attended by the hand of care and preservation. A misde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanour of <hi>Three Hundred Pound</hi> makes a great noise; yet proves perhaps but <hi>singly</hi> fatal, when the same Sum divided into Half-crown-Rapines shall destroy as many individual necessitous Families, impoverish'd before and altogether helpless, without creating any other sounds but those of <hi>neglected Lamentations.</hi> So that the Sale of such Offices is positively against the <hi>Tenth Commandment;</hi> as also against the Laws of the Land (as hereafter will appear.) For what greater injury can a Man do his Neighbour than to deprive him of the greatest right that is due to him! To debar him of that Justice which ought to be afforded him in his extremity? And not only in this manner to injure his Neighbour, but his <hi>poor Neighbour</hi> too, the particular <hi>Chart of God himself?</hi> For remedy of which, the Supreme Legislator made no Law, but frequent admonitions, as if man could not be guilty of so great an Impiety as to rob the Spital, which is an accumulated Murther. It is injurious to him that Sells: for how can he reach forth his hand to receive the free boons of Mercy from the God of pitty and compassion, while polluted with <hi>the price</hi> of Rapine, vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence and injury?</p>
            <p>The Sale of the Keeper's place of <hi>Ludgate, Newgate,</hi> with the <hi>Connters,</hi> &amp;c. brings me to urge this Text a little closser, and if I am not unhappy to beleive re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port, they were at <hi>Who gives most?</hi> A hainous demand in the Barter of those <hi>Shops of Cruclty!</hi> A strange piece of absurd severity! To sell the <hi>freedome</hi> of a <hi>Captive,</hi> An Usurpation certainly beyond Law (to sell that little liberty which the Law has left a <hi>Prisoner</hi>) to the disposal of a <hi>Turnkey.</hi> The Law makes him a Captive to his Creditor, and the Majestrate afterwards surrenders him up for <hi>Money,</hi> a Slave to his worse than <hi>Argier</hi>-keeper? Shall the Publick Houses builtat the City's charge be sold for private Lucre? So that every Room in a Prison becomes a <hi>Shop of Barbar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ism</hi> and Arbitary Power, where the Chief <hi>Bashaw</hi> of iniquity exercises an Inhumane Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranny, and squeezes thevery <hi>Faeces</hi> and <hi>Caput Mortum</hi> of a perish'd Estate as long as the least drop will <gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ome, by the same Art as they setch <hi>Oyl</hi> out of Bricks; first <hi>heat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> the poor Prisoner in the Fire of his threatning indignation, and then <hi>quenching</hi> him again in the sweet show of a little <hi>favour</hi> while any moisture of Gain appears.</p>
            <p>Here then lies the force of the <hi>Dilemma;</hi> Either a Prisoner for Debt may be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jured in Prison, or not. Either the Injuries repeated, are Injuries or none. If the Negative be allow'd; then all that has been already said has been to no purpose, and Holy Writ might have been more sparing of its Exhortations. If the Affirmative be asserted, then he that sells a <hi>Goalers Place, &amp;c.</hi> sells the Liberty, the Estate, the Person, nay, the very <hi>Lives</hi> of the Prisoners under his Jurisdiction, seeing that
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:59837:3"/>through the cruelty of their Keepers so many poor People have been stript to their naked Skins, and when all was gone, have been suffocated in Holes and Dungeons, to the loss of many of their Lives, Dishonour of our Nation, and scandal of the Christan Religion.</p>
            <p>But the Civil Law to which our own has nothing repugnant, informs us in the very words of that great Lawyer <hi>Ʋlpian,</hi> That a Prison is a Place of <hi>Restraint,</hi> and not of <hi>Punishment.</hi> That a Prison where there is hunger and thirst is no <hi>Prison,</hi> but a place of <hi>Torture.</hi> That no severe or bad usage is there to be admitted, where the Person in Debt remains, not as a <hi>Slave,</hi> but only as a <hi>Pledge,</hi> and security for the Creditors satisfaction. For which reason the Emperour <hi>Honorius</hi> affirmed, that it was the principal duty of a Judge, to be frequently inform'd by the Prisoners them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, of the State of their Captivity, that no Office of humanity might be wanting to men, lockt up in confinement. And so merciful were those Times, that if a Prisoner dyed in Prison, the Law presum'd it the fault of the Keeper; who was not to deny either Food or Bedding to the Person in custody.</p>
            <p>But purchas'd cruelty is now grown so bold, that if a poor Man pay not Extor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionary Fees and rackt; <hi>Chamber-Rent,</hi> he shall be thrown into <hi>Holes</hi> and <hi>Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sides,</hi> to be devour'd by Famine, Lice and Diseases. Which being so undeniable, I ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peal to the Tribunal of <hi>Justice</hi> it self, by what Law, or by what Authority, not claiming under the bad Title of Illegal Custome, any Sherriff who is the immediate Goaler himself, and ought to receive the custody of the Prisoner <hi>Gratis,</hi> can so un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kindly presume to <hi>Sell</hi> the Deputation of any Mans Liberty and Life to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troul of for did and imperious Avarice.</p>
            <p>I would fain know, for it is a <hi>Secret</hi> in Nature not to me yet reveal'd, by what surmize of common sence a <hi>Keeper</hi> of a Prison, can demand a recompence or <hi>Fee</hi> from a Prisoner for detaining him in Prison? There is an <hi>Admission-Fee,</hi> he cries. Alas! how is Man fallen from the Image of God and his <hi>Reason,</hi> to believe that any Person can deserve <hi>areward,</hi> for only opening the Door of misery and Destruction to annoy his Neighbour and common Friend? For being so kind as to admit him into the horrid Grave of Imprisonment? There is a <hi>Dimission-Fee</hi> too; but this altogether as absurd, to demand Mony for letting him go, that the <hi>Law</hi> has set free; for opening the Door to let him out of Custody whom the Receiver ought not to detain. For his <hi>Care</hi> in the interim, let <hi>them</hi> pay him that set him at work. The Prisoner is no way beholden to him for his Care: For 'tis <hi>that</hi> which he desires to be without. Therefore sayes the Civil Law in this case, if there be any thing due to a <hi>Keeper,</hi> it is due from the Creditor, whose duty it is to afford nourishment, and other supports of Life, to him, whom he keeps in Prison; and therefore the Keeper might refuse to take the Prisoner into Custody, till he had bargain'd with the Creditor for the Prisoners maintenance, as may be observed out of the Antient Volumes of the most Learned Civilians. But now such is the confi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence of a Purchaser, that to <hi>regain</hi> his Sum expended, he sells his <hi>Tap-House</hi> at pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digious Rates; So that where poor Men ought to have <hi>best</hi> and <hi>cheapest,</hi> they have the <hi>worst</hi> in <hi>qnality,</hi> and the <hi>smallest</hi> in quantity, which makes the price excessive. He Farms his <hi>Sheets</hi> to meer Harpies, and his great <hi>Key</hi> to such a peice of imperious cruelty, as is the worst of Mankind. And it is a shame to repeat the daily insolen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies and indignities, which the Prisoners and their Friends are forc'd to receive at their hands. But fee, I pray! Whether will not lewd Presidents at last lead us! It will perhaps be thought impertinent to dispute a Goalers demands for admitting us into his loathsome Mansions, when even the <hi>Common Hangman,</hi> no doubt encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raged by such examples, will scarce give a Malefacter a cast of his Office without a Bribe, demands very formerly his Fees, forsooth, of the Person to be Executed, and higgles with him as nicely as if he were going to do him some mighty kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness.</p>
            <p>As to the Civil Government of a Prison, no Argument perswades me to believe, that a <hi>Deputy Master</hi> is any way useful, otherwise than to see that the Prisoners be secur'd, well provided for and lookt after, as appears by the very Order of <hi>Ludgate,</hi> where the Prisoners taking their turns of Authority among themselves, far more patiently endure a Domestick, than a Forreign subjection: So that a Master Keeper, the meer Fungus and <hi>Toad-stool</hi> of a Sherrisss Authority, ought to find some better way to improve the blessing of his Inheritance, than by exposing it to the hazzard of Divine vengeance. There be those that say, the Dignity of the City Magistrate is here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:59837:3"/>by supported. But with what dishonour do these Men revile the City and the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gistrates of the City, at the same time? For so careful is the City to Elect Men of Estates proportionable to their Dignity, that there is no need of any Sinister assi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance to maintain the <hi>City-Grandeur.</hi> No ill got Gains, but <hi>Mercy, Justice, and upright Prudence,</hi> are the supports of a City. Is it not a goodly sight to see, the tears of the poor, congealed by a Frost of neglected Charity and Injustice into a <hi>Pearl</hi> glittering in the Ears of such or such a Lady? To be hold the Scarlet of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver's Majistracy dyed with the blood of helpless innocents, or the Purchase of Extortion? To see one of the chief Punishers of Iniquity drinking Healths of forget<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful plenty in Four Hundred Pound Goblets, the price of his own Infamy, and a Sergeants Roguery? Such sights as these perhaps we can only by conjecture guess at, but the All-seeing Eye of Heaven beholds all these <hi>blind Bargains,</hi> and it is the same thing whether the Accompt fall heavy on the <hi>Receiver</hi> or his Offspring.</p>
            <p>The disposal of Goalers Places, and especially the Keepers Place of <hi>Ludgate, &amp;c.</hi> In the trust whereof the <hi>Rich</hi> and <hi>Honest,</hi> not the Needy, and dissolute Designers of <hi>Prosit</hi> are to be imploy'd, is an Affair to be debated with a tender and charitable consideration, in which Prisons the poor enjoy (or at least ought to do) many Priviledges bestow'd upon them by the Piety of many good Men deceas'd, which are rather to be rescued from past injuries, than to be buried in the ruines of private Interest; nor are the Ashes of the Dead slightly to be disturb'd by oppressive inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation.</p>
            <p>Seeing then the Common Council of the City of <hi>London,</hi> who are the <hi>Representa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives</hi> of the People of the City, have interpos'd their Just Authority to stop the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gress of so great a clamour to Heaven, as the Sale of Publick Offices, and the Voice of the <hi>Just People</hi> is the Voice of <hi>God,</hi> those Men are chiefly to take care how they stop their Ears against that <hi>Sacred</hi> Sound, whom private advantage leads to make opposi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion against the same, lest in the day of their own calamity, they cry for Mercy in vain. <hi>London</hi> is a City whose Government deservedly challenges the Preemi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nence of any City now flourishing throughout the Universe. <hi>Rome</hi> the <hi>Mistress</hi> of the World could not Conquer her self; but oftentimes lay weltring in the blood of her own Citizens; nor could she hinder her own streets from being the Stage, whereon so many dismal Tragedies of intenstine Discord were Acted. Hear the Reason from the Words of One of her own Poets.</p>
            <q>
               <l>'Cause then they Justice basely Bought and Sold,</l>
               <l>And Antient Virtue was Post-pon'd to Gold.</l>
            </q>
            <p>But <hi>London</hi> has been Bless't with such a continued Calm of Peace for so many Centuries of Years, that never any City yet enjoy'd, so exactly has the perpetual Motion of its Authority in most other things been <hi>hitherto</hi> pois'd. Were it not great pitty that so harmonious a piece of Politick Government should be now di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sturb'd and disorder'd by violent Usurpation. <hi>Rome</hi> was only rich with the Prey of Rapine, wealthy in the Trophies of successful ambition: But <hi>London</hi> shines a famous Pile, Opulent in the gains of honest Industry. <hi>Rome</hi> the Mart of War and Slaugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter: <hi>London, Caesar</hi>'s <hi>Nobile Emporium.</hi> But Dam up the Current of her <hi>Meum &amp; Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um,</hi> sell her Seat of Justice, and how will all her splendor be Eclipst; <hi>Rome</hi> had only the dim Lamps of Morality, the obscure Lights of Sententious Epicurism and Stoicism to guide and instruct her: But <hi>London</hi> enjoys the most Orient Beams, the most unclouded Sunshine of Divine Truth and Doctrine. I am unwilling to urge it any further. <hi>Rome</hi> was a City, than which there was none in the World more care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full to relieve the Poverty of her Citizens, of which in the Times of her Innocencie she had many. No question but in <hi>London</hi> there are many good Men that unavoida<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly fall to dacay: Where could the City bestow her Places more Honourably than upon such? What could the City speak more Magnificent in History, than to boast that the very Train of her Magistracy, was sufficient to support the Chiefest and Choicest of her decay'd Members, content with the Lawful and modest Gains of their Employments? But on the contrary, what more dishonourable, than to sell her poor Citizens to be Dilainated and Macerated by the hand of Injustice, and for Money to make Slaughter-Houses and Shambles of her Houses of Restraint? For a City so fair<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly deckt with the pretious Jewels of Freedome and Priviledge, to sell the last remains
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:59837:4"/>of a Prisoners comfort? They then who have timely consider'd of these things, may well be encourag'd not to flinch from the maintainance of their most Noble enterpri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes: For it is the duty of every one that possesses a corresponding Talent, to af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford all the Arms of prevailing Arguments to active power, while employ'd in the Defence of Right and Truth, or he is a Betrayer thereof. This is no effect of Facti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Turbulancy, no Disturbance of the Civil Government, but rather a means to ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment and strengthen it with the sorce of Right understanding. Morality may Err, and the Pomp of Honour may prove forgetful; he then that only admonishes, and tells where such Errors may prove inconvenient, cannot, for that, be thought to have the less Reverence for his Superiors, or the smaller value for Authority: Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther is he to be accounted the Cities Friend, since he Breaths nothing but what tends to its preservation, and with an unbyast reality desires the increase of its renown, as much as he that with the most Cordial Motives of Interest wishes and prays for its well<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fare.</p>
            <div type="document">
               <head>Here follows an Appendix of the Law of the Land. now in force against the sale of Offices, with an Account of the Goalers and other Officers Fees, with their several Duties to the Prisoners.</head>
               <head type="sub">
                  <hi>Anno</hi> 5<seg rend="sup">o</seg>. 6<seg rend="sup">o</seg>. Edw. 6. <hi>Cap.</hi> 16.</head>
               <p>THe Penalty for Buying or Selling of some sort of Offices for the avoiding of Corruption which may hereafter happen to be in the Officer and Ministers in those Courts, Places or Rooms, wherein there is requisite to he had the true Administration of Justice, or Services of Trust, and to the intent that Persons Worthy and Meeet to be advanced to the Place where Justice is to be Ministred or any Service of Trust executed, should hereafter be preferred to the same, and no other.</p>
               <p>Be it therefore Enacted by the King our Sovereign Lord, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and the Commons in this present Parliament Assembled, and by the Authority of the same, That if any Person or Persons at any time here after Bargain or Sell any Office or Offices, or Deputation of any Office or Offices, or any Part or Parcel of any of them, or receive, have, or take any Money or Fee, reward, or any other profit directly or indirectly, or take any Promise, Agreement, Covenant, Bond, or any assurance, to receive or have any Money, Fee, Reward, or other pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit directly or indirectly, for any Office or Offices, or for the Deputation of any Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice or Offices, or any part of them, or to the intent that any Person should have exer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cise or enjoy any Office or Offices, or the Deputation of any Office or Offices, or any part of any of them, which Office or Offices, or any part or parcel of them, shall in any wise touch or concern the Administration or Execution of Justice, or the Receipt, Comptrolment, or Payment of any of the Kings Highness Treasure, Money, Rent, Revenue, Account, Aulneage, Auditorship, or Surveying of any of the Kings Majesties Honours, Castles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, Woods, or Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; or any the Kings Majesties Customes, or any Administration or necessary Attendance to be had, done or executed in any of the Kings Majesties House or Houses, the keeping of any of the Kings Majesties Towns, Castles or Fortresses, being used Occupied or appointed for a Place of strength and defence, or which shall concern or touch any Clarkship to be Occupied in any manner of Court of Record, wherein Justice is to be Ministred: That then all and every such Person and Persons that shall so Bargain or Sell any of the said Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations, or that shall take any Money, Fee, Reward, or profit for any of the said Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations, of any of the said Offices, or any part of any of them, or that shall take any Promise, Covenant, Bond, or Assurance for any Money, Reward or Profit to be given for any of the said Offices, Deputation or Deputations of any of the said Office or Offices, or any part of any of them, shall not only loose and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit all His and Their Right, Interest and Estate, which such Person or Persons, shall
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:59837:4"/>then have, of, in or to any of the said Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations' or any part of any of them, or of, in, or to the Gift or Nomiuation of any of the said Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations, for the which Office or Offices, or for the Deputation or Deputations of which Office or Offices; or any part of any of them, any such Person or Persons, shall so make any Bargain or Sale, or take, receive any Sum of Money Fee, Reward or Profit, or any promise, Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant or Assurance to have or receive any Fee, Reward, Mony or Profit: but also that all and every such Person or Persons, that shall give or pay any Sum of Money, Reward or Fee, or shall make any Promise, Agreement, Bond or Assurance for any of the said Offices, or for the Deputation or Deputations of any of the said Office or Offices, or any part of any of them, shall immediately by and upon the same Fee, Mony or Reward given or paid, or upon any such Promise, Covenant, Bond or Agreement, had or made for any Fee, Sum of Money, or Reward to be paid, as is aforesaid, be adjudged a disabled Person in the Law to all intents and purposes, to have,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Cook. lib.</hi> 12.78.</note> occupy or enjoy the said Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations, or any part of any of them, for the which such Person or Persons, shall so give or pay any Sum of Money, Fee or reward, or make any Promise, Covenant, Bond or other Assurance, to give or pay any Sum of Money, Fee or Reward.</p>
               <p>And be it also Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That all and every such Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gains, Sales, Promises, Bonds, Agreements, Covenants and Assurances as before Specified, shall be void, to and against Him and Them, by whom any such Bargain, Sale, Bond, Promise, Covenant and Assurance shall be had or made.</p>
               <p>Provided alway, That this Act, or any thing therein contained, shall not in any wise extend to any Office or Offices, whereof any Person or Persons is or shall be seized of any Estate of Inheritance, nor to any Office of Parkship, or of the keeping of any Park, House, Mannor, Garden, Chase or Forrest, or to any of them any thing in this Act hereto forementioned to the contrary thereof in any wise notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>standing.</p>
               <p>Provided also, That if any Person or Persons do hereafter ossend in any thing contrary to the Tenor and effect of this Act, yet that notwithstanding all judgments given, and all other Act and Acts executed or done, by any such Person or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, so offending by Authority or Colour of the Office or Deputation, which ought to be Forfited, or not occupied, or not enjoyed by the Person so offending as aforesaid after the said Offence so by such Person commited or done, and before such Person so offending for the same Offence be removed from the Exercise, Administra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, aad Occupation of the said Office or Deputation, shall be and remain good and sufficient in Law, to all intents constructions and purposes, in such like manner and form as the same should or ought to have remained and been, if this Act had never been had or made.</p>
               <p>Provided also, That this Act, or any thing therein contained, shall not in any wise extend to any Bargain, Sale, Gift, Grant, Nomination, Bond, Covenant, Promise, Agreement, or Assurance whatsoever it be of, or for any the Office or Offices, Deputation or Deputations aforesaid, or any part of any of them had, made, done, concluded or agreed before the First day of <hi>March</hi> next coming, but that the same Bargain, Sale, Gift, Grant, Nomination, bond, Covenant, Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mise, Agreement, or Assurance, had, made, concluded or a greed before the said First day of <hi>March,</hi> shall always remain, continue, and be in such force, strength and effect, as if this Act had never been had or made: Any thing before in this Act mentioned to the contrary thereof in any wise notwithstanding.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted by the Anthority aforesaid, That this Act, or any thing therein contained, shall not in any wise extend or be prejudicial or hurtful to any of the Chief Justices of the Kings Courts, commonly call'd the Kings Bench or Common Place, or to any of the Justices of Assize that now be, or hereafter shall be, but that they and every of them may do in every behalf touching or concerning any Office or Offices to be given or granted by them or any of them, as they or any of them might have done before the making of this Act: any thing above mention'd to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="document">
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:59837:5"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Cook.</hi> Rep. Lib. 12.78. <hi>Hill.</hi> 8. <hi>Jac.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this very Term in the Case of Dr. <hi>Trevor,</hi> who was Chancellour of a Bistop in <hi>Wales,</hi> it was resolved that the Office of a Chancellour and Register, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siastical Courts, are within the Statute 5 <hi>Edw.</hi> 6. <hi>Cap.</hi> 16. The Words of which Statute are, <hi>Any Office,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>which shall in any wise touch or concern the Adminstration or Execution of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stice;</hi> and the Words are strongly Pen'd against Corruption of Officers, for they are, <hi>Which shall in any wise touchor con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern the Administration,</hi> &amp;c. And the Preamble; <hi>And for avoiding of Corruption, which may hereafter happen to be in the Officers and Ministers of those Courts, Places, and Rooms, wherein there is requisite to be had the true Administration of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stice, in Services of Trust: And to the Intent that Persons worthy and meet to be advanced to the Places where Justice is to be Ministred, in any Service of Trust to be Executed, should be perferred to the same, and none other.</hi> Which Act being made for avoiding of Corruption in Officers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And for the Advancement of Persons more Worthy and sufficient for to Execute the said Offices, by which Justice and Right shall be also advanced, shall be Expounded most beneficially to sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>press Corruption. And in as much as the Law allows Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siastical Courts to proceed in Case of Blasphemy, Heresie, Schism, Incontinence, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the Loyalties of Matri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monies, of Divorce, of the Right of Tithes, Probat of Wills, granting of Aministrations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And that from these pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings depend not only the Salvation of Souls, but also the Ligitimation of Issues. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And that no Debt or Duty can be recovered by Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, or Administrators, without Probat of Testaments, or Letters of Administrations, and other things of great conse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence; It is most reason that such Officers, which concern the Administration and Execution of Justice in these Points, which concern the Salvation of Souls, and the other matters a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, shall be within this Statute, then Officers which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern the Administration or Execution of Justice in Temporal matters; for this, that Corruption of Offices in the said Spiritu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al and Ecclesiastical Causes is more dangerous, then the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers in Temporal Causes; for the Temporal Judge commits
<pb facs="tcp:59837:5"/>the Party Convict to the Goaler, but the Spiritual Juege com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits the Person Excomunicate to the Devil. Also those Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers do not only touch and concern the Administration of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stice, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But also are Services of great Trust, for this, that the pribcipal End of their proceedings is, <hi>Pro Satnte Ammarum, &amp;c.</hi> And there is no Exceptors or Proviso in the Statute for hem.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>It was resolved that such Offices were within the</hi> Pur-view, <hi>o<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the said Satute.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="document">
               <head>Here follows the Duty of Goaler.</head>
               <p>And now that Goalers, of what degree or state soever, may in some measure know the Duties of their respective places, and not through ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance or Impudence abuse such who are committed to their <hi>Charge.</hi> Here is an account what their Duty is to Prisoners, according to the Laws of this Land, which all Goalers are obliged under great Penalties to observe, and the People of this Land to preserve, as their Liberties, least by such neglect, slavery be insensibly drawn upon them.</p>
               <p>By the Common Law we find, as <hi>Bracton</hi> Lib. 3. fol. 105. <hi>Goalers are ordained to hold Prisoners, not to punish them.</hi> For Imprisonment by the Law is (neither ought to be) no more then a bare restraint of Liberty, without those illegal and uujust Destructions of close and open Prison (as is usual) See <hi>Stamf.</hi> Ple. Cro. sol. 70.</p>
               <p>Therefore <hi>Cook</hi> in his 3 Inst. 91. saith, <hi>That if the Goaler keep the Prisoners more streightly then he ought of right,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Britton sol. 18.</note>
                  <hi>where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the Frisoner dieth, this is Fellony in the Goaler by the Common Law. And this is the Cause, That if a Presoner dye in Prison,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Flet. <hi>lib.</hi> 1 <hi>Chap.</hi> 26.</note>
                  <hi>the the Coroner ought to sit upon him.</hi> See also the said <hi>Cook</hi> Fol. 34. <hi>Cap. Petty Treason;</hi> how Prisoners are to be used wherein is al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so an account of an Indictment of a Goaler for evil usuage of his <hi>Fol.</hi> 35. <hi>in Trin. Term,</hi> 7 E. 3. <hi>cor Regerot.</hi> 44.—That where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as one R. B. of T. was taken and detained in the Prison of <hi>Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coln</hi> Castle, for a certain Debt of Statute Merchant,<note place="margin">1 <hi>E.</hi> 3. cap. 7.</note> in the custo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of T. B. Constable of L. aforesaid; That the said T. B. put the said R. into the Common-Goal amongst Thieves, in a filthy Prison, contrary to the form of the Statute, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and there detained him, till he had paid him a Fine of 40. s. Whereupon <hi>Cook</hi> makes this Obser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, <hi>So as hereby it appeareth, where the I aw requireth that a Prisoner should be kept in safe and sure Custody; yet that must be without any pain or torment to the Prisoner.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>So <hi>Co.</hi> 3 Inst. 52. saith, <hi>If a Prisoner by the Dures, that it is hard us<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age of the Goaler, cometh to untimely Death, this is Murther in the Goaler.</hi> And in the Law implieth Malice, in respect of the Cruelty.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Horn,</hi> in the Mirror of Justice Page 288. saith, <hi>That it is an Abusion of the Law, that Prisoners are put into Irons, or other pain, before they are attainted.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>See also <hi>Cook</hi> 3 Inst. 34, 35.</p>
               <p>And <hi>Horn</hi> also Pag. 34. 36.<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Vox plebis</hi> par. 1. sol. 55, 56.</note> Reckons the starving of Prisoners by Famine, to be among the Crimes of <hi>Homi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cide</hi> in a Goaler.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:59837:6"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:59837:6"/>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:59837:7"/>
               <p>Which also <hi>Cook</hi> in his 3 Inst. Chap. 29. Title of <hi>Fellony</hi> in <hi>Goalers</hi> by <hi>Dures</hi> of Imprisonment, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by Statute and by the Common Law.</p>
               <p>And next, let ussee what the Law saith for the Fees due to Goalers, <hi>fol.</hi> 91. The Mirror of <hi>Justice,</hi> Page 288. tells us, That it is an Abusion of the Law, that Prisoners or others for them, to <hi>pay</hi> any thing for their <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries</hi> into the Goal, or for their <hi>Going-out:</hi> This is the Common Law, there is no Fee due to them by the Common Law. See what the Statutes say, The Statute of <hi>Westm.</hi> 1. chap. 26. saith. <q>That no Sheriff, or other Minister of the King, shall take Reward for doing their Offices, but what they take of the King, if they do they shall suffer-double to the Party agrieved, and be punished at the will of the King.</q> Under this word, <hi>Minister</hi> of the <hi>King,</hi> are included, <hi>all Escheators, Coroners, Goalers, and the like.</hi> See <hi>Cook</hi> 2 Inst. fol. 209. affirms. And agreeable is <hi>Stamf. pl. Coron.</hi> 49. Nay by the Statutes of 4. E. 3. Chap. 10. Goalers are to receive <hi>Thieves</hi> and <hi>Fellons,</hi> taking nothing by way of Fees for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of them. So odious is this Extortion of Goalers that very Thieves and Fellons are ezcept from payment of Fees.</p>
               <p>And we find in our Law-Books, That no Fees are due to any Officer, Goaler, or Minister of Justice, but only those which are giuen by Act of Parliament; for if a Goaler will prescribe for any Fees, the Prescription is void, because against this Act of Parliament, made 3 E. 1. being an Act made within time of Memory, and takes away all manner of pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Fees before; and we are sure none can be raised by colour of prescrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion since: And therefore we find by the Books of 8. E. 4. fol. 18. <hi>That a Marshal or Goaler cannot detain any Presoner after his discharge from the Court, but only for the Fees of the Court</hi> (the Court being not barred by this Statute of <hi>Westm.</hi> 1. aforementioned) <hi>and if he do, he may be Indicted for Extortion.</hi> And agreeable to this is the Book of 21. F. 7. fol. 16. where amongst other things its held for Law, <hi>That if a Goaler or Guardian of a Prison, takes his Prisoners proper Garment, Cloak, or Money from him, it is a Trespass, and the Goaler shall be answerable for it:</hi> So that we may undeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably conclude, That there is no Fee at all due to any <hi>Goaler</hi> or <hi>Guardian</hi> of a Prison from the Prisoner (but what is due unto him by special Act of Parliament.</p>
               <p>And if a Goaller or Guardian of a Prisoner, shall take any thing as a Fee of his Prisoner, he may and ought to be <hi>Indicted</hi> of <hi>Extortion,</hi> and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on conviction to be removed for his Office; and if his Prisoner, by Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>straint, Menace, or Dures, be enforced to give him Money; he may re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover that Money against the Goaler again, in an Action of the Case at Common Law.</p>
               <p>Item,<note place="margin">Stat. 23 H. 6. Chap. 10.</note> The King Considering the great Perjury, Extortion, and Oppression, which be and have been in this Realm by his Sheriffs, Under-Sheriffs, and their Clarks,<note place="margin">Stat. 4. H. 4. 5,</note> Bailiffs, and Keepers of Prisons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> hath ordained by Authority aforesaid, in eschewing all such Extortion,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Rast.</hi> predict. fol. 318.</note> Perjury, and Oppression, that no Sheriff shall let to Farm in any manner his Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, nor any of his Bailiwicks. Nor that any of the said Officers and Ministers,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Cook</hi> predict. 365.</note> by occasion, of under colour of their Office, shall take any other thing by them,<note place="margin">21. H. 7. fol. 16.</note> nor by any other Person to their use, profit, or avail, if any Person by them or any of them to be
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:59837:7"/>Arrested or Attatched, for the ommitting of any Arrest or Attatchment to be made by their Body, or of any Person by them, or any of them (by force or colour of their Office Arrested or Attatched) for Fine, Suit of Prison, Mainprise, letting to Bail, or shewing any Ease or Favour (to hny such Person Arrested or to be Attatched) for their Reward or Profit; but such as follo&amp;, that is to say, For the Sheriff 20 <hi>d.</hi> The Officer which maketh the Arrest or Attatchment, 4 <hi>d.</hi> And the Goaler of the Prison if he be committed to Ward, 4 <hi>d.</hi>—And that all Sheriffs, Bailiffs,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Rast.</hi> predict. fol. 371.</note> Goa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers, or any other Officer or Ministers, which do do contrasy to this Ordinance, in any Point of the same, shall lose to the Party in this behalf indam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage or grieved, his trebble Dammages,<note place="margin">Stat. 21. <hi>Ed.</hi> o.</note> and shall forfi the the Sum of 40 <hi>l.</hi> for every such Offence, the one Moiety to the King, the other to the Prosecutor, to be Recovered at Common Law, in either of the Courts of Kings-Bench, or <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> at <hi>Westminster.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is a perfect Account of the Goalers Fees in all Cases, where Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons are laid in Prison upon Civil Matters and Causes, which Fee of 4 <hi>d.</hi> is more then any other Statue or Law allows them to take from their Prisoners: But in such Chses where the King is Party, its established, <q>That the Prisoners in all the Kings Prisons should be maintained at the Kings Charge, and out of the Kings Revenues, according to the Old Law of the Land, much less to have Money extorted from by the Goaler.</q> But look into the Prisons in and about the City of <hi>London,</hi> what horrible Oppressions, Extortions and Cruelties, are Exercised upon the Free-born People of <hi>England,</hi> yea in most Prisons throughout this Kingdom.</p>
               <p>So that by the Laws of the Land it appears, that those who Sell, or take any manner of reward for any Publick Office or Palce, or those who do receive any greater Fee than therein is exprest, have no more Property, Right or Interest to do, than the Pyrate has to the peaceable Merchant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans Ship, a Robber to the innocent Traveller's Purse, or the Wolf to blood of the Lamb: And incase such Laws as those are not to be Obser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, who can be assured to enjoy their Rights, Liberties, nay, their Wives, Children or Estates, longer than it pleaseth the will and pleasure of Cruel, Ravenus and Mercenary Extortioners, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> who stick not to turn Butchers to the Peoples Priviledges, and Conspirators against their Liberties, <hi>&amp;c?</hi> What Game such Persons play at you may guess, and I would with case express; but Modesty engages me at this time to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bear; since the Generality of this City and Nation too, have been strick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en with an amazement to see the many Breaches herein, against the very Face of Law, wrested to Usher in Oppression. Judgment is turned back, Justice in this Particulars stands a far off, and our Antient, Just, and Fundamental Laws of Mercy, are turned into a shadow, and they who endeavour to reclaim such Evils draw on themselves the Frowns and Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>please of Such and Such.</p>
               <p>But as God's Indignation rested upon the Children of <hi>Israel,</hi> till <hi>Achan</hi>'s Theft was discover'd and punisht: So this City suffers sore Judgments, till it purgeth it self of those many <hi>Achan</hi>'s that lodge in her Bosom, and live upon the Ruine of her most necessitous Inhabitants.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>James Whiston.</signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>